We will take the two primitive aortas.
In the middle, there are some inner tissues, here.
Nutritional.
Remember, the embryo, what does it do? It grows.
It is an influential reference to the neural plate,
which becomes a groove.
In this formation of a groove, it creates a pathway.
This pathway starts to take shape.
small primitive aortic conduits, and we see that the embryo
makes a flexion movement,
of internal rotation, adduction. A developmental movement where it returns to the center,
just because at some point, I have my aortas developing here and I have
a process of telencephalization pulling backward, and everything comes closer to the front.
In this phase of moving forward, I initially had embryologically
two tubes that were there. These two tubes will come toward the midline and
at some point
they will fuse. This fusion phase, here, you
see that through this process, it
starts to come together like this. There is still a bit of
inner tissue,
no problem. There is less and less. And at some point
the two tissues here,
will really be side by side.
As there is no more inner tissue,
a decaying field appears.
You have a lot of things like this happening in the body.
An example, at first, I am like this,
I have what we call branchial arches.
When I have a flexion of the embryo,
we see appearing outside on the ectoderm.
on the inside, a compression,
I can feel this with my finger,
and we see it forms branchial arches.
At one point here, there is a branchial arch
that exerts pressure against the heart with the jaw,
creating an exhausting pressure,
which opens up an area here, the mouth.
This is, for instance, an example of a decaying field.
Now, for example, when we exceed
a limit, an example of a decaying field, you are hospitalized,
you lie in your
bed for fifteen days, three weeks, what starts to happen? You start
developing a pressure sore. You have pressure continuously, you lose feeling in
the side,
and in fact, you lose trophic aspects. You first notice a warm area
and then at some point, you have a decaying field, and you develop.
It's a new structure that appears.
and this phenomenon
of the decaying field
in your system
and the development of the vascular system
you will see is very important.
it changes all the time.
At first, you have what we call
the cardinal veins,
anterior,
and then posterior.
then it will evolve into subcardinal veins,
then supracardinal veins,
and you will have a complete reorganization
of your body's organization based on that, depending on your growth, etc.
These are simply fields, and then you have the spinal arteries, posterior vessels, etc.
At first, you have a structure, and then through these fields of compression, decompression, etc.,
new structures appear, this is what we call a decaying field.
So it's like the word "destruction," I don't like it, it's a change of form.
We will see the field, what we call "the loosening field," an art field.
This field will explain to you a suction field. It's the same
pattern for all glands in the body.
This type of field always appears along the surfaces of epithelial tissues,
whether of ectodermal origin,
or of endodermal origin. I will take an example
of epithelial tissue of
endodermal type. And below, what do I have? I have connective tissue,
which contains
vessels, small glands, a matrix that has fibers, etc.
We see appearing along the surfaces at some point, in a very early stage, a congestive phase.
As if there was accumulation, as if it was a little bit of water that
came in.
The image is like when I massage on the beach, you see.
where the ground is a bit congested,
but when you walk on it, you feel it can sink in.
It's as if it was in the draft stage, that's the moment at the start.
It's an activity, I come, and suddenly there's quicksand.
We will take the lung; remember how the diaphragm is set up.
There is a space here behind; why? Because I have my... let's say...
My digestive tube is here, like this, and behind, here, there is
this tissue, here, behind, just this phenomenon happening here, a
fragilization, and at some point, due to the growth of the embryo, and the straightening,
the elongation of my embryo, the growth here, a space opens up
here, and it creates a field where the tissue
that is there,
the epithelium is like sucked into this space.
Do you understand what I mean? It's really like a suction cup.
I grow and I pull toward me.
A suction field, I suck.
The epithelial tissue suddenly goes down into the connective tissue.
It's like it's being pulled into the connective tissue.
First phase, we see that it is...
like sucked into the tissue, collapsing into the tissue,
into a suction field. It is still around the connective tissue.
And there, I find myself with two types of movements.
Either the cell descends and really creates a gland,
like this.
And there, it will be called an exocrine gland,
the cells will secrete a substance that will be put in the lumen
created by the tube here, for example, the
gallbladder, an exocrine type gland, or
if it goes further into the metabolic field, it will create what we call
an endocrine gland.
Here it disappears, and only a gland remains right here; it will be called an endocrine gland,
meaning it will secrete the substance outside.
And what is there? There is my entire vascular network; I will take this
into the blood.
On the lung it remains, on the liver it remains,
But under the pancreas, you have two pancreases, you have the exocrine pancreas and the endocrine pancreas,
it is a metabolic field that developed in a suction field that occurred at the same
time, but the image is that some have gone further here, they lost
their connection; they became simple small islands of
small glands inside the system, which produce another metabolic plan
of aminocrine type.
while the areas, it's a gland that will manufacture the insulin system, for example.
The lungs should be considered as a gland; it is a respiratory gland.
It’s the same development algorithm but in different spaces
and in different timelines.
It’s a negative question at the pulmonary level.
which is maintained by the system.
If I cut the breach of the parietal system,
the lung becomes its original shape.
That's why we create the vacuum.
And in fact, these are suction mechanisms; it’s the void.
It maintains, you see.
This is not a difference of metabolic field,
it’s a difference in growth.
So it’s the same field, but it encompasses the same field.
One will be a bit stronger and lose its connectivity.
It's
all the organs
of epithelial origin,
but life at the beginning
is like a great suction field
the environment and the regeneration.
Initially,
you have the environment
and on the tissue
you have activities,
you have many molecules
that will release morphogens
that will greatly
But what is the environment of the electrical field, what is the environment and what is the environment
in your article map?
So there, we saw, for example, the first metabolic field, it was how it will
organize corrosion fields to create new structures.
And the extreme case of a decaying field is a pressure sore, but here, it’s
a destruction, but it’s a destruction of inner tissue.
That’s why...
on the other side, it was also a destruction
of inner tissue, but with the appearance
of a new structure.
Whereas in the sore,
it's just the inner tissue
that is damaged.
Through this process,
we begin to perceive
how in the developing embryo
it will appear,
based on your genome,
based on space and time,
the different metabolic fields
that will start participating in this creation.
We each have a metabolic field.
And if I go too far into a system,
I will disturb that entire field over there.
That's the idea of homeostatic guarantee.
Everyone must at some point reach their state of balance.
This is a dilation field.
We are in a structure that is building.
I have a tissue type, at some stage,
a mesoblastic tissue
that appears.
And by, which is at a certain periphery,
by, at some point,
growth,
I pull on the tissue,
and the tissue,
will begin to elongate
in one spot. But it still retains
its elasticity.
And so, it fills with elastin,
it retains its elastin.
And if now, I move to another field,
I go further
I pull this field, I go to another type of tissue. So depending on
the field it will
receive, you see, in the growth, where it will be placed in the space, how it will
organize.
If I go beyond a dilation field, I will have a retention field. You
see,
if I go further into my retention field, I will have a retraction field. I
am
with you here. We are first thinking that it's a muscle.
But the tension is too strong in that phase.
We become, wait, not yet, a ligament above, or a fascia.
But now, we keep pulling more and more,
and you see, it retracts like this, it’s as if it is retracting.
And we completely lose the liquid structure, and we become a bone.
So, we have a field here, of our units.
On another level, we can have a dilation field.
I am in dilation.
If it continues, it will give a retention field.
So this is all the muscles,
this includes all ligaments, all fascia.
This produces all the bones.
And this is another way
the bone appears. Because you saw
in the bone,
we saw that there was membranous bone
and cartilaginous bone.
So it all depends on whether it will undergo a field
of compression
or decompression in its formation.
The vault is a tissue that...
grows by expanding.
The base is a tissue that forms under compression.
And here, we add another metabolic field
called contusion fields
or diffusion fields.
In other words, these fields
are fields where the cells are compressed,
which will create cartilaginous tissues,
but it’s also all the mechanisms,
the whole establishment of a metabolic tissue.
of metabolic growth movement,
the contusion field and the diffusion field.
Here, it will give different types of tissues.
So here we have a bit of a global image
that needs to be seen in the developmental growth,
where each tissue will reach a balance
depending on its destiny and bodily situation, its genome and its environment
in its growing strength,
everyone will at some point maintain themselves, as I said.
If we go too far, normally I would have here a
tendon, and then if I go too far, it will become a calcifying tendinitis.
So I start from a retention field to something denser.
I lose metabolic qualities at the tissue level.
Okay? Do you understand?
And it's there, our role, it's to globally maintain this
homeostatic principle
through these primitive embryonic fields that organize this process
and maintain it.
It's where all this embryonic force finds its meaning.
Which is always there, is a guarantor of this...
homeostasis because it achieved at some point
a balance.
This is this great balancing act that happens
with always this reference
to maintain
its potency.
It's a large field here.
You have the liver, you have a stomach, you are each
a balance. Everything is fine.
You are in harmony,
in homeostatic balance
relative to the system. If one starts
to go off, one starts
to eat poorly.
They start eating junk food, things, they change their metabolism.
What do the tissues do? They will respond differently.
And suddenly, I develop hepatomegaly, damn, less blood is flowing, I develop
hypertension.
I develop hypertension, my nervous system starts acting up.
And you start going off, and what do the tissues do?
They will first try to maintain themselves, oh, what’s going on? We need to change a bit.
It felt like a tendinitis was coming.
In a bench, huh.
We will say that it will calm down
then the heart
starts to degenerate
then the body wants to reject
at first it will do because you have different
magnets than you, it will use
different things, first
it will try to eliminate the disease
then if it doesn’t work, it will
up to the point where it creates neoformations
it’s all substrates
so we need to try to find
the layers we can be in
and help the person to...
to change back. And we had seen
that at the base, it was the first
course, practically the first dia
important, the chronology of the emergence
of communication systems.
I often invite people,
all my patients, they will go out, and they will want
at least to try meditation.
I try to lead them
to themselves,
to self-chronologize,
self-chronologize,
you said that?
Can you imagine, I have cells that...
There are two cells pushing against each other.
There is a mitosis happening.
It’s a contusion field.
But at some point, a contusion field pushes, it will laterally create a field of
dissolution.
So it’s just simply, you just have to hold for one, one makes young cartilaginous tissues,
the other makes cartilaginous tissues after the young ones.
Dissolution will engender a decaying field or will engender...
a field of closure; everything self-equilibrates.
But don’t worry,
next time, I will begin
to do this, and when I develop,
I will add all the fields. And there we will start
to suddenly have a sort of
movement of the fields.
Because this is just seen on a tissue level.
Then you have
all the cellular organization,
then you have all the molecular organization, then you have
all the homeostatic organization, atomic,
subatomic, and you
really keep this phrase in mind:
the sacrum is the base of cortical development
if the sacrum is free
the vertebral axis is free
if the vertebral axis is free
the medullary aspect is free
if the medullary level is free
the skull is free
the sacrum is something I check
every time anyway
cleared sacrum point
by any means
you do it
the sacrum must
all synchronizations
this is an important synchronicity
already here with the peritoneum
so the neural tube is a joint
with the cavity
cardio-peritoneal
and we can even say that
the urogenital axis
by its level of creation
by its mesodermic force
of development is the joint
between the two
the meso is the joint between endo and ecto
because here we need to restrict
the entire vascular system to really understand this diagram.
It’s the importance of the brain with the liver, with the heart, with the lungs, with
the plexus
or the enteric system and with the renal system. We develop, it interferes in the
functioning.
This is the micro-time, this is a bit later. These are the synchronicities and this is
later too; not now.